ANATOLY YAKOVENKO

aeyakovenko@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | resume

SUMMARY

Software developer with over 10 years of experience in embedded operating systems, shipping software on millions of units, developing <u>patents</u>, leading projects and contributing to large groups including <u>Linux Kernel</u>, with a focus on performance and optimization for Qualcomm ARM and DSP processors.

SKILLS

Hardware and Systems

 Embedded Operating Systems, RTOS, Linux Kernel, Android, Qualcomm MSMs, System MMUs, ARM, Hexagon DSP

Languages and Tools

• C, Haskell, Make, Lua, Python, Ruby, Bash, C++, Java, Git, Perforce, GDB, JTAG, Trace32

WORK EXPERIENCE

Qualcomm, San Diego CA

Senior Staff Engineer Manager, 2015 to Present Senior Staff Engineer, 2012 to 2015 Staff Engineer, 2008 - 2012 Senior Engineer, 2006 - 2009 Engineer, 2003 - 2006

OpenDSP

- Lead Architect of a brand new technology for utilizing DSP subsystems on Qualcomm chipsets for next-generation high-performance applications.
- Commercial applications include Augmented Reality, Virtual Reality, 3D Camera processing, 4K video post-processing, and GoogleX's Project Tango.
- Technology used by all major OEMS, such as Samsung, LG, Google, Xiaomi, OnePlus.

BREW

- Core kernel developer for BREW's Operating System.
- Built critical features such as application sandboxing, device driver framework, interprocess communication, system call tracing tools, IDL compiler for network transparent objects.
- Shipped to thousands of different handsets and in millions of units.

QChat

- Software developer for server components of a Push2Talk service.
- Implemented various network protocols such as SIP/RTP/HTTP, and high performance logging and tracing tools for a large distributed system with over 40 components.

Alescere LLC, Lisle IL

Co-Founder, 2001 to 2003

• Founding member of Alescere, a VOIP startup

 Lead development of SIP and <u>RTP</u> protocol stacks and server components for a VoIP system for small businesses.

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

Research Assistant, 2003

- Developed a web server that supports QoS for HTTP requests
- Designed a probabilistic scheduler for the Linux kernel
- Implemented a roaming protocol for 802.11a/b networks for NetBSD

Personal Research

 Neural Networks, Genetic Algorithms, Markov Models, and Bayesian Inference Algorithms

References

- Brian Kelley, Senior Director of Technology, bkelley@quicinc.com
- Rob Walker, Senior Director of Engineering, rwalker@quicinc.com
- Ramesh Chandrasekhar, Senior Director of Engineering, rameshc@qti.qualcomm.com

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, 2003